yo yo yo welcome viv I'm gonna hand this
over to you we are here you know why the
best shitty music turn off this thing is
so commute alright so we are here in our
Honda Civic and we are going to self
drive to Best Buy so let's see this this
one any this one's hard for humans so
this one you have a pork
[Music]
so 2000 the best place well then I'm in
a coma yeah yeah one of these days you
know once we have the nav integrations
gonna be a good day
Wow 41 people already 40 more people are
ready to show me so this is zero point
three point three this is the latest
open source released which has the best
model of all the models I've ever seen
with open paws
um and it's really thanks to the crowd
it's thanks to you know we're now
training on all the data from every
other user of open pilot so all the cars
make each other smarter people always if
people asks I'll just read it out
Bonjour
can you buy this no it's even better you
don't need to buy it free yeah we've put
the plan so this is running this is a
common deal which we have free plans for
available on the internet or there are
third parties which have taken our plans
and made them available for sale um this
is software's called open pilot and it's
one under set free licensed under the
MIT license and you can just go to our
github and download it so I do need to
disengage here because this is a red
light and open pilot does not yet
support red lights or stop signs
is this a neo with is this a neo with
panda this is actually the there's a
panda inside of this neo so yes it is
the neo with giant panda compatible cars
um but it also works with the old neo
board compatible cars right now are the
Honda Civic the Acura ILX the newest
addition the Honda CRV and soon once we
get it up streamed the Chevy Volt so I
did have to disengage for this red light
doesn't work in traffic yes yes it works
in traffic
um if you saw it was just working in
traffic
let's wait for this light to turn green
I'll get us up to speed well you ever
make a video tutorial on how to port
cars maybe so if you saw my last
periscope stream we are
yeah and that's good oh you're holding
it to try to not cover the antenna I
remember antenna gate and that bummed if
you watch my last stream I show off the
initial stuff we do for the Prius which
shows you how to maybe connect a new car
now we're gonna get another
disengagement up here probably unless
this light magically turns green so it
will work as long as you went up the
first car at the light it works at
lights but you know we're not the first
car at the light so I'm gonna have to
manually disengage it for this red light
up here just like Tesla autopilot Volvo
Drive Thailand every shipping system
today there's not a single shipping
system today which will stop for red
lights but red lights are not really
that hard and you know we don't just
make open pilot we also make a dash cam
app called shiver we use this ship for
data and not just training the
self-driving cars but also to make maps
now the trick when you're making maps
isn't just to know what intersection the
lights are at but it's important to also
know exactly where the light is that
corresponds to the place that you stop
if you're chewing gum on the Paris yeah
come on with Casey Casey nice that you
can I do this in a brand new Civic you
can do it at least brand new Civic it's
super easy you just need to unplug one
wire and plug it into our thing and then
when you want to switch it back you
and you know what your back why I red
lights hard and when we think was
supportive red lights are not that hard
and we will see certainly moves in that
direction this year when will math major
getting to open pilot oh yeah well we'll
be moving in this direction this year as
well
little hard on the brakes there the
reason it was a little bit hard on the
brakes there is because the radar by
default filters out stopped cars but
when it fuses with the vision system it
can stop for car to stop cars so that
was a fully stopped car it's kind of
hard for the radar to see it hard for
the radar to distinguish them say like a
manhole cover anything with Honda
sensing radar aligner so it uses the
built-in radar from the car obviously
there's no lidar lidar is overpriced
someone's yeah there's not that much
that a lidar really helps you with as
part of the driving problem that you
can't do today using modern deep
learning and computer vision with
cameras oh asking for wine will level-3
itami be available when the statistics
show it's ready um so I would expect it
first from Tesla slowly followed up by
us
so let's see how it does here look at
take a look at the lines on the road
they're very confusing
alright so steer control saturated is
when we've exceeded the steering torque
limit of the car on the torque limit is
a safety feature put there by Honda not
by us to prevent any sort of these
systems from jamming the wheel super
here we're just gonna put the speed up
here manually 265 yeah once we do maps
will integrate the speed limit
automatically
the speed limits actually only 45 so
we'll be going first absolutely yeah
well it is open source 150 MIT license
or do we support them we give them
support you know but can they do it of
course license yeah we haven't we
encourage in the city now one of these
days the neo will tell you this stuff -
Sarah Monty Boulevard all right
when dishonored by myself having heard
[Laughter]
jokes man friendly jokes override the
haunted for better we already can but
for safety reasons we don't
Wabble there
you know they got acquired for a lot of
money they're not the worst they're not
the worst there's there's there's much
worse people out there to mobile I you
know the CTO really did start to change
his tune about self-driving I think they
were took a ridiculous position on the
Tesla thing why is it better than Tesla
system why is ours better than Esso
system because you can put it in your
twenty thousand dollar car test the
system what is the pan to do well the
Panda is a universal car interface so
the Panda basically allows computers
like the Neo or like a computer or like
your smartphone to plug into your car so
the Panda basically allows full access
to your car over either USB or Wi-Fi to
keep driving for a bit so you can keep
talking
what's our company name or kamidana add
your comment on a I uh and actually we
are doing arms forgot our work we're
launching our first product of for sale
this Friday so we announced this on our
Twitter first product for sale this
Friday we're open to press Wednesday and
Thursday by appointment price free so
open pilot I'll brief the product the
product price is obviously not been
announced
because the product hasn't been
announced yet but it will be for sale
point two oh this is your yeah I know I
know for a little bit
you know what does the end goal for a
kid like this - cosmic future um well
the entry-level stuff should be under a
thousand then if you want fancier stuff
maybe I'll keep it under five minutes
would there be a subscription fee very
possibly yes
not yeah no subscription fees an open
file it will always be free it's not
like we're ever gonna start charging for
the current version of exhibit we love
our civic we did just buy a Prius top we
love our Prius - but we love our saving
as well so we've been self-driving now
for about four minutes you can see
that's the bar right there
when that bar runs out the system makes
sure that you're paying attention by
forcing a user action to happen at three
on six minutes if that bar runs out the
thing will beep and ask you to take
control which can also happen for
several other reasons if I can to torque
without raiding potentially will offer a
camera only solution no pilot without
the actuators you need you need the car
to be able to turn the wheel hit the
brakes in to get something really launch
a product like sensors for cars which is
not as senses
yeah I mean that's sort of what it is
the knee out of the neo is the census we
again we don't we don't sell them house
insurance coverage work with
self-driving well so right now these are
level two systems so Tesla show them at
level two systems make driving slightly
safer when used in conjunction with a
person so you are I'm still the legal
operator of this vehicle
all right I'm a legal operator of this
vehicle up even though it's in yes they
can um so you can buy we recommend the
Delfin ESR 2.5 it's a really nice radar
if you want to use the simplest one to
get started with is the night act that
ships in these hot might I might um
this model feels good yeah right like
it's no waffles this is a big
improvement
well the 2010 pre has worked with ok if
you have a Prius with lka maybe l kan
ACC to really be supported but the Prius
but because it's a hybrid hybrid usually
have brakes that are more activatable so
are you gonna see what happens right now
when the health bar run down its gonna
start beeping and it's gonna ask me
at sunset of that
nice
does your product work in bad traffic
good on gas product where's your traffic
and it's excellent on gas like most
critical systems way better than you
save the environment baby look the
health bar is really about to run out
right now so let's say I'm not paying
any attention take control to regain
speed and eventually the car will start
to us I'm gonna take control back
is 0.33 master version 0.33 is master
version yeah it's actually shipped I'm
so I'm just gonna reengage here freak
error no no no this is this is caused by
something else so this probably won't
happen in the release version of open
pilot this is actually trunk open pilot
so I'm gonna have to power cycle the car
so I'm just gonna get off the next exit
quickly power cycle the car and there be
a short periscope guys can you take you
to any time yes you definitely can
course you can if you step on either
pedal the system will immediately
disengage and the amount of torque that
it's capable of putting on the steering
wheel is super small so if you steer the
system doesn't disengage but you can
override how much it's turning the wheel
with one pinky what if you don't take
until after the alert it slows it it
slows down yeah it stops accelerating
will continue to steer but it stops
accelerating
and soon we will probably have support
if you have the right connection to turn
your hazard lights on yes right right
periscopes forever you guys will there
be shops offering installation and setup
oh do you want a shop yeah do you want a
shop Accord support a court support is
almost done rose driveway we do not
endorse with this guy
nope all right there's got a power cycle
yes if this happens when things lag a
little bit so I'm gonna go home and I'm
gonna review this event like I said this
actually isn't zero point three point
three um this is an internal version of
open pilot which probably has this box
it's called a regression for a
reasonable Cydia the iPhone jailbroken
Appstore um so comedy I kids are based
on Android um so
it's estimated insulation install and
setup oh the times it's super fast it's
like I said it's really one connector
I'll show you guys when we pull into the
Best Buy parking lot just how easy it is
right let's get back on the highway here
this is not running silky smooth a silky
smooth is very beta right now you know
we're a little bit behind Tesla in that
way petrol to get us on the highway here
I'm gonna have to do the lane changes so
open toilet itself can do lane changes
but the reason we don't support it is
because we don't have a safe way of
knowing whether your blind spot is clear
the phone only has one forward facing
camera disengage our website is kamidana
high for that question and what's on the
Best Buy shopping list what is the best
buy shopping list well so let's just say
the press is coming by on Wednesday and
Thursday so we're getting them know so
the law for most states just states that
you have to have two mirrors I can see
behind the vehicle and I have them
they're called my left there and my
right now
-
oh if you've already found the blind
spot messages well uh let's talk do we
have any tech components
not really no I mean I figured we'll
start to see them soon once everyone
figures out how often this ideas but I'm
so getting off Sara Monty Boulevard 47
article
forget it 47 I will show you guys in the
parking lot well right now if your car
has Lane keep assist and adaptive cruise
control it's a good bat that it's
compatible I was actually the hardest
time again for Oakland pilot to because
the Sun is so low in the sky doing
pretty well
people think nighttime is hard item is
actually easier than daytime because
there's so much contrast between the
lane lines and everything else now the
machine learning goes to our trailer do
we think kids are short-term business
yeah I mean eventually you know I think
about I think about like a serious
satellite radio right it used to be that
you would buy a radio and put it in your
car then it just started to get included
with all the cars some of them by the
manufacturer but some of them at the
dealership
so the path forward for kamma about
working with car manufacturers is
impossible these companies are dinosaurs
now working with dealerships is a whole
lot more possible so we expect that a
lot of cars you buy will have self-drive
capabilities pre-installed but maybe not
from the manufacturer
getting a lot of good shots you know
they know I'm not doing anything right
there's a self-driving car you know
we're not just periscope with me shipped
on put your feet higher up so you can
see yeah you can see what the yeah so we
sat at 70 miles an hour now we're going
48 because it's broski in front of me in
slow
are you gonna work on left right turn
season 2017 Kristensen as partners
yes
Tech stop signs and speed limits we
don't have to detect a speed limits or
stop signs you know what they are right
so as long as you know where the car is
you know what to do a red light you have
to just detect whether they're red or
green not necessarily I ever thought of
taking about my approach and licensing
Oh mobilize seems more concerned with
how many units they sell and less
concerned with the quality of those
units I'm a lot more concerned to the
quality of the units
one point two miles
they're stoked I mean we're fun that's
sort of the way it is like to say Toyota
wanted to put this in their cars or say
we're in a Honda say Honda wanted to put
this in their cars we'd be happy to give
it to Honda under the same terms we'd
give it to any individual which is right
now if Honda would like to use this it's
free Honda could literally ship their
cars with this stuff for free and it way
better than their system it's gonna do a
lane change here without disengaging
I'll show you what it does so I have my
blinker on I'm just gonna turn I'm gonna
let go of the wheel here it's gonna pull
me right back and point what do you do
with the shipper data we make maps and
train so technical
are you the creator yep sure
we have cutting everything to see a
thing
garbage
that's a John Daly Bulevar oh don't you
see I have notice this one all right
very cool let's go that way car when we
have auto lien change like Tesla as soon
as we're in cars that have the right
sensor so Tesla's using the ultrasonics
for that which is a little bit sketchy
but for example the Prius we actually
shipped a 6% increase to torque in the
in the latest version co-pilot you know
a little bit more than highway it's
obviously very good at highways but um
for this kind of stuff like on south and
north
yeah the limit is six minutes before
yeah best part as far as pies not that
far we drove a little bit extra for the
for the good folks on the
yeah I mean soon maybe even before we
ship ride like the stop signs will ship
navigation built in to open violent
she'll be able to type in your
destination and even if it can't make a
turn it will tell you we're starting to
need to take it we'll be able to make
some turns when there's like a fork in
the road it'll be able to choose Ken
McGann's be used to generate driving
data reducing the need to
you can't you again expert you want come
work build me some good cans some
whoppers a PK oh let's get Walker's love
BK we do well at Best Buy we get some
whoppers do you still use the CNN
architecture that you polish on github
last year no we never use that
architecture man that was that was just
some research code not by an intern our
architecture is not public but you can
reverse-engineer the vision deep on air
we ship with open file this is me
driving so yeah yes of course if you
have a supportive car which right now is
only the Honda Civic see that turn is
diamond
yeah so the Civic support stop-and-go
it'sit's just a limitation of how you
control the gas on the car
so our ILX actually supports stop and go
even though it doesn't by the
manufacturer because we built a gas
pedal interceptor and maybe we'll
release instructions about how to do
that
the codes already notice a single lane
support they're asking women single I'm
sure if you're like a one lane road so
wow the most people came on favorite
American people care about Best Buy you
want a live stream best buy two people
have asked that a large investor install
parking can make slow turns yeah I mean
you can't make it can't put a lot of
torque in the wheel so if you gotta like
really turn the wheel basically anything
you can do with a finger it can do where
are we single lane markings not singling
oh yeah
show us how to shop George show you had
a sharp show you livestream Best Buy
today gas price not gonna stop me
alright alright alright let's let's do
you have people all right let's
livestream Best Buy let's see if we
start to get a lot of drop-off well I'll
leave but so I'll reveal what we're
doing we're gonna buy some big-screen
televisions to show off our analytics to
the press we have some awesome analytics
now we have like big maps of where all
our users are and stuff so I'm gonna
show this all off to the press when they
come by Wednesday or Thursday for our
launch which will be available for sale
on Friday follow us on Twitter I'll show
you a little bit about how installation
works right so on this Civic I remove
the rear view mirror I can't encourage
you to do this because the Ruby mirror
is considered a safety feature here so
we actually encourage people now to use
a GoPro mount and mount it underneath
but if you do individually decide to do
this we believe it is legal so this
isn't new so you can see this is running
base UI here this is an internal
internal build not as good as the
external builds that we actually um so
these are like all my previous drives so
I can go through and I can see them on
here let's see what they look like this
is a little slow because we're actually
restricting this app to one core because
we leave the rest of the cores available
for the self-driving system but now that
it's clearly not self-driving it should
be able to use more I'm so I can kind of
you know pan through my route here this
is all in the cloud so you don't have to
worry about storage space on the device
you can see the little car icon is no
because we're not connected to a car but
um yes this was a drive looks like
someone went to the airport I don't
always drive this car this cars
available to our employees so yeah that
we're going to Best Buy we really were
self driving y'all missed it I don't
think we should show up we'll come back
we're coming back
on the way home and periscope that too
yeah baby so what we bought yes it's
it's exhausted I love Best Buy and I
don't like ant show off all my
enthusiasm parents let's go through this
so this is a common neo we built it
are the instructions are available for
free at our github github.com slash
comma AI also you can buy them from to
third parties have sprung up and set up
little neo sale shops um they usually
include this cable which goes from this
rj45 it's not Ethernet it has two can
buses on it and power to this Jie
connector which is how you plug into the
Honda alright so if this was a new car
whatever rearview mirror and I will
cover here you just pop off this cover
this plug is usually plugged in to this
thing here so this is the stalk self
driving system in the Honda you know
some people say that your sting only
supports the same stuff as the stock
here's what I encourage you to do buy a
Honda
try this talk and if you're happy with
that you don't need our stuff like a
little cute camera it's got easy links
Zink FPGA inside of it we used to call
it the mobile I actually did not have a
mobile ID chip in it um so we shouldn't
what's the word libel eyes mobile
acquired for a lot of money if that was
their goal then you know judge people by
their own goals so yeah this is the
stock system and you see that our thing
has the same connector as the stock
system so let's put that back in there
you don't even have to remove it you
just leave it unplug this one wire like
just one wire into here take this wire
plug it in Junio remove your rear view
mirror that's done with one screw all
right but I can't tell you to do that um
and then just slide on like this and you
are good oh this is a J connector we
bought off of digi-key um you can find
other connectors on dookey yeah if you
wanna know where we get the aquarii get
the equipment what equipment they're
saying where'd we get all the equipment
like this thing yeah so the plans for
this are available on our gear
you can also buy them for a few third
parties but a lot of it you gotta make
you know this is still this is still all
very early we were talking about selling
a product last year we announced it but
then you know for for regulatory reasons
and for you know we just couldn't
provide a true consumer product so we're
like let's go the hobbyist route it's
kind of like oculus let's ship some
things that are a whole lot more like
development kits and then let's work up
to an eventual consumer product now the
kind of thing soccer moms can use we
will be back we will be will be back
well we won't be that quick I love best
oh and bobbers and watch him eating a
whopper while the car drives sob does
the point if you join if you join when
we parked you will see a self-driving
yeah well you can just go back and you
can see